home insurance and automobile
insurance might be must-haves
but it doesn't have to cost you an arm and
a leg to have the appropriate coverages
there are things you can do to get discounts on
your homeowners insurance and automobile insurance
here are some helpful tips to save money on
your insurance premiums tips on discounts for
homeowners insurance security you get discounts if
you have a security system installed in your home
a gated community tends to have lower
insurance rates and lower rates of crime
something as simple as dead bolt locks might even
give you a discount on your homeowner's insurance
fire safety equipping your home with smoke
detectors and carbon monoxide detectors
are great steps to lowering your insurance
rates going a step further with fire sprinkler
systems fire escapes fire extinguishers and heat
detectors will help lower your insurance premiums
maintenance making updates to the wiring
of your home having a high rated roof that
is hail resistant updating your pipes having hand
rails along staircases or a gate around your pool
are all things that can get you a discount on your
homeowner's insurance no claims in 10 years if
you haven't filed a claim in the last 10 years you
could be eligible for a discount to your insurance
talk with your provider about any other
policy discounts that you might be eligible
for that you may not have thought of in the
past tips on discounts for auto insurance
safe driver if you've had no at fault accidents or
traffic violations then you should be able to get
discounts on your car insurance safety features if
your car is equipped with certain safety features
then you could be eligible for discounts
on your insurance ask your agent if they
offer discounts for things like airbags
anti-lock brakes and automatic seat belts
anti-theft device if your car comes equipped with
an anti-theft device then you get discounts for
that you can also install your own alarm
system or a vehicle recovery transceiver
student discounts most insurance companies
will offer discounts for students who maintain
a certain grade level in school since most
insurances will charge young drivers more
until they are 25 maintaining a certain
gpa can be a great way to get discounts
on your insurance for drivers who are 25
and younger don't let your insurance lapse
if you're thinking about finding a new insurance
provider then do it early don't wait until your
insurance lapses aside from the fact that you
can't drive your car if it's uninsured you can be
eligible for a discount for maintaining insurance
constantly when you switch to another company
the biggest key to getting the best rates
on your car insurance is shopping around
be sure to ask each insurance company what kind
of discounts they offer to their customers so you
can be sure you're getting the best rates and the
most discounts possible that are available to you